

MakMendelson

Contact



443 854 0819



mak.mendelson (at) gmail.com



forekast.github.io



twitter.com/AltF4WillHelp



linkedin.com/in/makmendelson

Skills

- User Interface Design
- User Experience Design
- User Experience Testing
- Product Development
- **▶** Game Development
- Adobe Illustrator
- **▶** Game Design
- Logo Design & Branding
- Business Cards & Stationary
- Adobe Photoshop
- Digital Painting
- Concept Art
- **▶** Blender
- ▶ 2D & 3D Animation
- Texturing
- Fine Art

Languages

- **English**
- 😯 Russian
- Spanish

Summary

I had the fortunate experience of beginning my career with the **co-founding, managing, and developing** of products at a small video game company, right out of college, for nearly four years.

I've since worked as a User Interface Designer for a government contractor, as well as an independent design contractor. I'm looking to continue building experience while further developing my skills and abilities in the creation of easy-to-use and visually appealing UX and digital art, or, otherwise, take part in creative design and development with a skilled team.

I hope to one day be well equipped enough to (re)found my own videogame company, and, this time, I'll be building it upon a much more robust foundation.

Experience

Independent Contractor

February 2017 — Present

CANDA Solutions

http://candasolutions.com/

- \cdot Wordpress-based site development, supplemented by working knowledge of HTML & CSS http://freshhaystack.com/
- · Consulting on Mobile application design
- · Branding design & development, to represent various Services-Offered by CANDA
- · Design of various client-facing Marketing, Presentation, and Show Booth materials

User Interface Consultant and Tester

December 2014 - June 2016

Buchanan & Edwards

http://buchanan-edwards.com/

- \cdot Consulted, generated high-fidelity mock-ups, and tested User Interfaces in the development of a Knowledge Management Tool web application for the Department of State
- · Collaborated with Business Analysts to collect, define, and document client requirements
- \cdot Collaborated with Developers to determine best implementation strategies, and to ensure product is inline with current design mock-ups
- · Developed Branding and Stationary
- · I have a Current DOD SECRET clearance

Co-Founder and Visual Artist

April 2010 - February 2014

Gradient Studios. LLC.

http://www.gradientstudios.com

- · Co-founded Gradient Studios, LLC. right out of college
- · Lead Artist
- · Developed Start-to-Finish, and Shipped two games of our own Intellectual Property
- · Determined and Designed aesthetics for several games
- · Created UI and game assets for several games
- \cdot Created promotional material: trailer/gameplay videos, posters, booth design
- Took part in securing seed funding from Accomplice (formerly of Altas Ventures)

Helpdesk Consultant

August 2006 - May 2010

Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute

http://rpi.edu/

 $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$ Provided Software at the Computer Center to Students, Faculty, and Staff

Education

Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute

2006 - 2010

BS, Games & Simulation Arts & Sciences, Concentration in Electronic Arts

Gilman School 2002-2006

High School Diploma